假设我是网络
let's say I'm the web
我们在上一节中编写的服务器
server we wrote in the previous section
我是浏览器
and I'm a browser
假设我向您发送请求
and let's say I send you a request
好吧，我处理请求
well I handle the request
发回响应
send back a response
这很好用
and that works pretty good
如果我们只是偶尔收到请求
if we only get requests once in a while
但假设我们同时收到五个请求
but let's say we get five requests at the same time
好吧，现在我一次只能处理一个请求
well right now I can only handle one request at a time
所以我拿第一个
so I take the first one
发回回复 谢谢
send back a response thank you
拿第二个
take the second one
发回其响应
send back its response
但是当我收到第 5 个请求时
but by the time I get to this 5th request
好
well
它可能已经排了很长时间的队
it's potentially been waiting in line for a long time
我们得到的请求越多，这条线就越长
and the more requests we get the longer the line grows
这是我们服务器的瓶颈
here's that bottleneck in our server
在 hdp 的异常循环函数中的位置
where in the except loop function of the hdp
服务器文件，你会记得这个
server file and as you'll recall this
除了这里的函数是一个阻塞调用
except function here is a blocking call
它暂停执行
it suspends execution
在此侦听套接字上等待客户端连接
waiting for a client connection on this listen socket
当它接受新连接时
and when it accepts a new connection
然后客户端套接字将在这里绑定
then the client socket is going to get bound here
然后我们把它交给这个
and then we hand that off to this
在这里提供功能
serve function right here
这将是关于
which is going to go about the process of
实际处理请求并返回响应
actually handling the request and returning a response
所以我们必须等待这个服务函数返回
so we have to wait for this serve function to return
在我们可以再次调用 except 循环之前
before we can recurs calling except loop again
这使我们回到这条线
which takes us back up to this line
等待下一个客户端连接
waiting for the next client connection
所以让我们用一个请求来模拟这个问题
so let's simulate this problem with a request
这需要相对较长的时间来处理
that takes a relatively long time to handle
是的，我们将在此处的处理程序模块中完成此操作
yeah we'll do that over in the handler module here
我将在这里粘贴一条新路线
I'm going to paste in a new route up here
并且该路线称为休眠
and the route is called hibernate
因为这就是熊所做的
because that's what bears do
所以我们要在休眠斜杠上进行模式匹配
so we're going to pattern match on hibernate slash
接着
and then
我们想休眠一段时间
we want to hibernate for a certain amount of time
所以我们要绑定变量时间
so we're going to bind the variable time
到该网址中休眠后的任何数字
to whatever number comes after hibernate in that url
现在这将是一个字符串
now that's going to be a string
所以我们要花时间
so we're going to take the time
然后我们要管它
and then we're going to pipe it
将字符串转换为整数以将其转换为整数
into string to integer to convert it to an integer
然后我们想睡那段时间
and then we want to sleep for that amount of time
而earling有一个模块叫做
while earling has a module called
我们在那里调用的计时器
timer which we're calling right there
它有一个叫做睡眠的功能
it has a function called sleep
需要多少毫秒才能休眠
that takes the number of milliseconds to sleep
所以我们只是要插管
so we're just going to pipe in
那个时候进入睡眠功能
that time into the sleep function
我们学会了如何使用耳环
and we learned how to use an earling
上一节中的库
library in the previous section
然后我们就回去
then we're just going to return
状态码为 200 的响应
a response with the status code of 200
和尸体
and the bodies
只是想说
just going to say
嘿我醒了
hey I'm awake
现在稍微简化一下输出
now to simplify the output a bit
我要评论这个
I'm going to comment out this
在我们的管道中记录插件
log plugin up here in our pipeline
然后让我们继续启动我们的服务器
and then let's go ahead and fire up our server
我们做ix mix
we do ix mix
我们会说服务 hdp 服务器
we're going to say serve hdp server
开始，我们将再次在端口 4000 上启动它
start and we're going to start it on port 4000 again
好的，我们的服务器正在运行
okay we've got our server running
现在让我们尝试向它发送请求
now let's try sending it a request
所以回到这个
so back in this
终端会话就在这里，我将再次使用 curl
terminal session right here I'm going to use curl again
我要向 4000 api 斜线熊发送请求
I'm going to send a request to 4000 api slash bears
所以你注意到我们几乎立即得到回复
so you notice we get back a response almost immediately
服务器是
and the server is
现在等待接受下一个客户端连接
now waiting to accept the next client connection
所以现在在这个窗口中让我们发送一个请求
so now down in this window let's send a request
休眠所以我们要休眠 10,000
to hibernate so we're going to hibernate for 10,000
那是[&#39;十&#39;，&#39;千&#39;]毫秒
that's ['ten', 'thousand']millisecond
这将是 10 秒
that's going to be 10 seconds
好的，它正在冬眠
all right and it's hibernating
现在如果我们尝试运行 api 熊请求
now if we try to run the api bears request
好吧，我们没有立即得到回应
well we don't get an immediate response
这个挂了
this one's hung up
仍在做它的工作，而这个正在等待它
still doing its work and this one's waiting for it
一旦我们从中醒来
and as soon as we get back awake from that
长时间运行的请求
long running request
那么我们也得到了我们的 api 熊的响应
well then we also get the response for our api bears
所以它不会处理 api 请求，直到
so it doesn't handle the api request until
在休眠请求完成后
after the hibernate request has finished
是的，没错
yeah that's right
事实上，如果我们向上滚动，我们可以看到
in fact we can see that if we scroll up
在服务器输出中
in the server output up here
所以正在等待接受客户端连接
so is waiting to accept a client connection
我们发送了一个休眠 10,000 的请求
we sent in a request for hibernate 10,000
它收到了那个请求
it received that request
然后它发回响应
then it sent the response back
说它醒了
saying it was awake
然后它又回到等待
then it went back to waiting
用于下一个客户端连接
for the next client connection
该连接被接受，这就是
that connection was accepted and that was the
api 承载请求
api bears request
然后它继续
and then it went ahead
并为此发回响应
and sent the response back for that
所以如果我们回顾一下我们的代码
so if we look back at the code in our
此处的服务器，除了此处的行
server at this except line right here
如果客户端尝试连接到服务器
if a client tries to connect to the server
当它忙于处理一个长时间运行的请求时
while it's busy handling a long running request
这将在服务中处理
which is going to get handled in serve
然后连接请求被放置
then the connection request gets put
在所谓的积压 q
in what's called a backlog q
并告诉
and tell
服务器完成处理当前请求
the server finishes handling the current request
只有这样它才能循环回来
only then can it loop back
最多接受挂起的客户端连接
up to accept the pending client connection
因为我们一次只能接受一个连接
and because we can only accept one connection at a time
api 请求在 backlog 中停留了 10 秒
the api request sat in the backlog for 10 seconds
如果积压已满
and if the backlog fills up
默认情况下它最多只能容纳五个连接
by default it can only hold up to five connections
然后拒绝任何新连接
then any new connections are rejected
这不好
and this isn't good
我们需要修改服务器来处理
we need to modify the server to handle
多个请求同时进行
multiple requests concurrently
这样请求就不会延迟
so that requests don't get delayed
我们还有另一个问题需要解决
we also have another problem we need to address
假设一个异常被引发，而
let's say an exception gets raised while
处理请求
handling a request
好吧，我们将用一条新路线来模拟它
well we'll simulate that with a new route
我将把它粘贴到我们的休眠路线上方
and I'll just paste it in above our hibernate route
在处理程序中
here in the handler
这个请求的路径只是斜线kaboom
and the path to this request is just slash kaboom
然后我们使用
and then we use the
光线在这里起作用
rays function here
使用字符串 cab 引发异常
to raise an exception with the string cab
现在你可以防御性地添加
now you could defensively add
一些捕获此异常的异常处理
some exception handling that catches this exception
并返回 500 响应
and returns of 500 response
但我们现在就这样吧
but let's just go with this for now
是的，我会把它保存起来，然后回到这里
yeah I'll save that away and then back over here
我需要重启服务器
I need to restart the server
现在如果我们发送可以请求会发生什么
now what happens if we send that can request
所以我会下来
so I'll come down here
虽然我们在这里看到运行时错误
while we see the runtime error up here
在服务器日志驾驶室中
in the server log cab
你注意到我们回到了 ix session 终端
and you notice we're back at an ix session terminal
所以发送那个请求
so sending in that request
它关闭了整个网络服务器
it brought down the entire web server
如果我们来到这里并尝试运行请求
if we come here and we try to run a request
对于 api 熊
for api bears
好吧，它只是挂起
well it just hangs
很明显我们的服务器不是很容错
so clearly our server isn't very fault tolerant
仅处理一个请求的异常或任何故障
an exception or any failure handling just one request
使整个服务器陷入困境并影响所有人
makes the entire server go poof and impacts all
其他要求
other requests
所以我们需要一种方法来同时运行每个请求
so we need a way to run each request concurrently and
保持每个请求隔离
keep each request isolated
听起来有点棘手
that sounds kind of tricky
但实际上
but it's actually
使用长生不老药过程相当简单
fairly straightforward using elixir processes
事实上，这就是长生不老药真正闪耀的地方
in fact this is where elixir really shines
在接受循环函数中
in the accept loop function
我们有这个我们称之为接受的顺序代码
we have this sequential code we call accept
然后我们调用 serve 并等待它返回
and then we call serve and wait for it to return
然后我们再次调用接受循环
and then we call accept loop again
回避备份
which recuses back up
我们只是通过这里
and we just go through here
运行这些功能的锁定步骤
lock step running these functions
但我们想运行这个函数
but we want to run this function
这里的服务功能是一个单独的过程
this serve function right here is a separate process
异步而不是顺序
asynchronously rather than sequentially
那就对了
that's right
这样我们就可以接受任何新的客户端连接
that way we can accept any new client connections
其他请求同时
other requests while at the same time
处理当前请求
handling the current request
换句话说，我们可以同时处理请求
in other words we can handle requests concurrently
那么我们如何将代码作为一个单独的进程运行
so how do we run code as a separate process
好吧，我们使用 spawn 功能
well we use the spawn function
并且有两种方法可以调用 spawn 函数
and there are two ways to call the spawn function
使用匿名函数和命名函数
with an anonymous function and with a named function
让我们从一个匿名函数开始
let's just start with an anonymous function
我们会在我们的性爱会议上做这件事
and we'll do that over in our sex session
所以 spawn 是在上校模块中定义的
so spawn is defined in the colonel module
所以它会自动导入
so it's automatically imported
这意味着我们可以像这样调用 spawn
which means we can just call spawn like that
然后它需要一个匿名函数
and then it takes an anonymous function
所以我们将使用 fn
so we'll use fn
然后在那个函数里面
and then inside of that function
我们只是要打印出你好
we're just going to print out howdy
如果我点击返回
and if I hit return
当它运行这段代码时
while it ran this chunk of code
io 将我们置于单独的进程中
io put us howdy in a separate process
我们看到它打印出来了
and we see that it printed out
你好回到这里的性爱会议
howdy back here in sex session
我们也得到了一个叫做 pid 的东西
and we also got this thing called a pid
由 spawn 函数返回的
that was returned by the spawn function
并且 pid 是唯一标识符
and the pid is a unique identifier
运行的进程
of the process that ran
在这种情况下，它被处理了 166
in this case it was processed one sixty six
现在你的会有所不同，因为好吧
now yours is going to be different because well
这是一个不同的过程
it's a different process
现在让我们看一下这个的慢动作回放
now let's look at a slow motion replay of this
是的，让我们再做一次
yeah let's do it again
这次我想做一些改变
this time I want to make a couple changes
我想捕获pid
I want to capture the pid
所以我们要绑定
so we're going to bind
pid 到左侧的 pid 变量
the pid to the pid variable on the left hand side
然后在里面
and then inside
在打印你好之前在这里
here before printing howdy
我想睡5秒
I want to sleep for 5 seconds
所以我要调用那个定时器模块睡眠函数
so I'm going to call that timer module sleep function
再次
again
然后将多个表达式放在同一行
and then to put multiple expressions on the same line
我将在此处使用分号
I'm going to use a semicolon right there
这样我就不必做
that way I don't have to do
六个内的多行表达式
multiline expressions inside six
所以我们要睡5秒
so we're going to sleep for 5 seconds
然后打印出你好
and then print out howdy
如果我们点击返回
and if we hit return
当我们立即得到 pid 时，它是 pid 170
while we immediately get the pid back it's pid 170
然后这个过程正在进行中
and then the process is working on
这个匿名函数，所以它睡了 5 秒
this anonymous function so it slept for 5 seconds
然后当它完成时它打印出你好
and then when it was done it printed howdy
我们在这里看到了
and we see that right here
所以让我们再试一次
so let's try that again
这次我要改成10秒
this time I'm going to change it to 10 seconds
然后我们可以检查它是否正在运行
and then we can check that it's running
Elixir 中有一个流程模块，并且有一个 live
there's a process module in elixir and there's a live
问号功能
question mark function
我们可以调用并传递 pid
we can call and pass it the pid
它还活着
it's alive still alive
还活着
still alive
哎呀，现在我们回来了，你好，它还活着吗
oop now we get back howdy so is it alive
不，现在进程已经死了
no now the process has died
它打印出了你好，它不再活着
it printed out howdy and it's no longer alive
运行匿名函数后
after running the anonymous function
生成过程已退出
the spawn process exited
稍后我们将看到如何使用 pid
a bit later we'll see how to use the pid
作为向进程发送消息的地址
as an address to send messages to a process
但是现在让我们回到我们最初的问题
but for now let's go back to our original problem
是的，您可能会看到它的发展方向
yeah you probably see where this is heading
我们说我们想运行这个服务功能
we said we wanted to run this serve function
在一个单独的过程中
in a separate process
现在我们知道该怎么做
and now we know how to do that
我们只是要产生一个进程
we're just going to spawn a process
我们将放置一个匿名函数
we're going to put an anonymous function
就这样调用服务
call serve just like that
在这种情况下，我们不需要 pid
and in this case we don't need the pid
所以我不会在左侧绑定它
so I'm not going to bind to it on the left hand side
所以现在一旦我们在这里接受了客户端连接
so now once we've accepted a client connection here
我们只是要产生一个新的过程
we're just going to spawn a new process to
处理请求
handle the request
这意味着我们要撤退
which means we're going to drop back
进入这个接受循环
into this accept loop
很快，因为这将运行
pretty quickly because this is going to run
在后台异步
asynchronously in the background
事实上，因为它在后台运行
in fact since it's running in the background
我要添加一些输出
I'm going to add some output
在这里服务
down here and serve
因为这会得到
because this is going to get
在那个单独的进程中运行
run in that separate process
我们只想看看 pid 是什么
and we just want to see what pid is
实际上做所有这些工作
actually doing all this work
所以我要使用它
so I'm going to use it
我想打印过程的坑
and I want to print the pit of the process
正在运行此功能
that's running this function
你可以这样做的方法是调用 self
and the way you can do that is call self
即返回当前进程的坑
that returns the pit of the current process
然后我需要对它进行插值
and then I'm going to need to interpolate it
像那样和我们要显示的pid结构
like that and the pid structure we want to display
只是以某种容易看到的方式
just in some way that's easy to see
所以我要使用检查
and so I'm going to use inspect
所以我们要检查 pid
so we're going to inspect the pid
这将基本上给我们我们在 ix 中看到的内容
that's going to give us basically what we saw in ix
然后我只想说
and then I'm just going to say
正在努力
working on it
现在一旦我们产生了这个
now once we've spawned this
过程将完全靠自己
process it's going to be all on its own
我们基本上可以忘记生成过程
we can essentially forget about the spawn process
因为它可以访问这个客户端套接字
because it has access to this client socket
它通过它
through which it
将 hdp 响应发送回浏览器
sends the hdp response back to the browser
一旦得到回应
and once the response has been
在进程即将退出时发送
sent while the process is going to exit
那么当我们产生一个进程时会发生什么
so what happens when we spawn a process that
不使用套接字
doesn't use a socket
这是一个更常见的情况
which is a more common scenario
好吧，我们将在下一节中讨论
well we'll look at that in the next section
现在让我们重新开始
for now let's just get a clean slate
通过重新启动它和服务器
by restarting it and the server
现在让我们再次尝试该休眠请求
now let's try that hibernate request again
我们将休眠 10 秒
we'll hibernate for 10 seconds
如果我们在这里抬头
if we look up here
我们看到我们接受客户端连接
we see we accept a client connection
但它几乎立刻又回来了
but it almost immediately comes back
并开始等待下一个客户端连接
and starts waiting for the next client connection
即使这个休眠请求仍在运行
even though this hibernate request is still running
所以现在让我们再次发送休眠请求
so now let's send the hibernate request again
和
and
在一个单独的窗口中，我们将发送我们的 api 请求
in a separate window we'll send a request for our api
你看
and you see
我们的 api 立即得到回复
we get a response back immediately for our api
在我们的休眠请求完成之前
before our hibernate request even finishes
那是因为 api 请求
and that's because the api request
被单独处理
was handled in a separate
并发进程
concurrent process
所以现在发送我们的出租车请求
so sending our cab request now
不应影响服务器或任何其他请求
shouldn't affect the server or any other requests
是的，在服务器窗口中
yeah up in the server window
我们看到引发了异常
we see that the exception got raised
出租车就在这里
here's cab right here
但是您注意到我们没有返回到税务会话提示
but you notice we don't return to an tax session prompt
因为服务器不受影响
because the server isn't affected
它仍在运行，实际上它仍在响应
it's still running and in fact it's still responsive
我们可以发送请求，所以我要发送一个
we can send requests in so I'm going to send one in for
只是熊
just bears
正确的得到了那个请求并得到了回复
right got that request and got a response right back
或 api 熊
or api bears
服务器仍在响应其他请求
the server still responding to other requests
如果我们在服务器中向上滚动
and if we scroll up in the server
我们应该看到
we should see the
处理这些请求的进程的投标
bids of the processes that handled those requests
所以这里进程 170 正在处理它
so here process 170 was working on it
这里进程一六十九正在处理它
here process one sixty nine was working on it
我想你明白了
and I think you get the point
每个请求都由不同的进程处理
each request was handled by a different process
这很酷
this is pretty cool
每个客户端连接都有自己的
every client connection gets its own
隔离一个请求失败的过程
process isolating the failure of one request
从另一个是的
from another yeah
只需将一些现有代码包装在 spawn 中
simply by wrapping some existing code in a spawn
运行我们的网络服务器现在更容错
function our web servers now more fault tolerate
并且可以同时处理多个请求
and can handle multiple requests concurrently